# MICHAEL SAMARA

3100 BARTON POINT DRIVE AUSTIN, TX 78733 · (737) 701-0185 · MICHAELSAM08@GMAIL.COM

Github Repositories: https://github.com/michaelsam08?tab=repositories

## **SUMMARY**

Michael is a versatile and guick learning Web Developer. Broadly knowledgeable in React, JavaScript, Express, MongoDB, Node.js, CSS and HTML. An effective process-driven developer who creates and implements applications for businesses and individuals. Collaborative team player with the ability to effectively communicate at all organizational and education levels. Exceptional problem solving skills, strong business judgement, and demonstrated experience contributing to and leading cross-functional teams.

## **EXPERIENCE**

WEB INK Austin. TX **Role: Sole Proprietor** August 2018-Present

- Write and refactor code for educational and small business applications
- Develop UI pages in React.js and connect with MongoDB

**AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY** 

Austin, TX Role: Tutor October 2018-Present

- Provide individual and small group tutoring to students of Austin Coding Academy
- Assist students in improving academic achievement by meeting with them on a regular basis to clarify learning objectives

#### TEACHING ABROAD AND VIRTUAL CLASSROOM

Roles: ESL Instructor, English Teacher

Remote & Abroad 8/16-10/18

- Research and design development plans for children and adult learners ranging from Beginner Level through Business English and TOEFL preparation
- Develop interactive lessons utilizing technology, enabling students to understand and use English both inside the classroom and in their daily lives
- Create daily lesson plans, materials, and assessments to develop ESL central areas: grammar syntax, listening, reading, speaking and writing
- Participate in planning and training sessions for classroom technology integration

#### **USAA** INVESTMENT COMPLIANCE MANAGER

San Antonio, TX 2007-2015

Previous Roles: Sales Manager, Relationship Manager

- Led teams of financial advisors to maximize sales potential and relationship reinforcement with clients.
- Built collaborative relationships with business partners across the enterprise to create line of sight for financial advisors and leaders.
- Performed data analysis to identify trends, create and implement plans to meet organizational objectives.
- Built multi-generational relationships through various communication and marketing channels

Delivered solutions to that meet individual high networth members' financial needs

## CITI-SMITH BARNEY FINANCIAL ADVISOR, PRODUCT MANAGEMENT

Boston, MA 2003 - 2007

Austin, TX

 Performed product research, comparison, and change implementation with vendors for annuity and publicly traded equity investments with a \$150 MM client-base.

## **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

Student, AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY

January-September 2018

Full Stack Software Engineering 2018

- Front end competencies: React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- Back end competencies: Express, node.js, MongoDB
- Familiarity with Slack and Github for collaboration

### **Bachelor of Arts, CLARK UNIVERSITY**

Business Management

• Co-founder Entrepreneurship Club

Worcester, MA December 2005

## PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS & COMPETENCIES

- Problem solving
- Process improvement
- Instructional design and training
- Data visualization
- TEFL (certified to Teach English as a Foreign Language)
- TOEIC (Test of English for International Communication)
- Chartered Retirement Planning Counselor
- Completed all Certified Financial Planner modules
- FINRA Series 24, 7, and 66